hey guys so this is an interesting
problem we have 5 to the x plus 2 equals
71 plus 5 to the x plus 5 squared and
let's know what is 5 to the x so we're
not solving for x here we're solving for
5 to the x but first let's copy it down
on the left hand side i see an exponent
being added so i'm going to use these
notes right here a to the b plus c
equals a to the b times a to the c we
copy down our 5 to the x plus 2 this is
going to be equal to 5 to the x times 5
to the 2. and we can drag that up here
and get rid of all this stuff and then
for the right hand side let's just copy
everything down this 5 squared is equal
to 5 times 5 which is 25 and this 5
squared is also 25 and let's just bring
everything else down this 71 plus this
25 is equal to 96 and then this 5 to the
x i'm going to call it 1 5 to the x and
on the left-hand side this 5 to the x
times 25 i'm going to call this 25 5 to
the x's we don't want to have x's on
both sides so i'm going to subtract 1 5
to the x from both sides on the
left-hand side i'm going to have 24 5 to
the x's and on the right hand side i'm
just going to have 96 then i can divide
both sides by 24. on the left-hand side
i just have the 5 to the x and on the
right-hand side 96 divided by 24 is
equal to 4. we were being asked to solve
what is 5 to the x well the answer is 5
to the x equals 4. we can put a box
around it and we're now done how
exciting